刚开始看时，重音移动可能显得很随意，但我们来
When you first look at it, the stress shifts may seem arbitrary, but let's
分析这五个例子背后的逻辑，并用它处理其他
examine the logic behind these five examples and use it to go on to other,
类似情况。一，An American guy。起作用的词是 American。Guy 甚至
similar cases. 1. An American guy. The operative word is American. Guy could even
可以省掉，而不改变短语意思。比较 I saw two American
be left out without changing the meaning of the phrase. Compare I saw two American
guy、man、kid、lady 这类泛指人的词，
guys yesterday with I saw two Americans yesterday. Words like guy, man, kid, lady,
people 这类词，在以人为中心的语言里实际上类似代词。另一方面，强名词
people are de facto pronouns in an anthropocentric language. A strong noun,
而后者会被重读：They flew an American flag。这就是为什么
on the other hand, would be stressed. They flew an American flag. This is why you
会出现模式变化：Jim killed a man；he killed a snake。二，An American
have the pattern change, Jim killed a man, he killed a snake. 2. An American
restaurant。不要被普通描述性短语带偏，只因为里面
restaurant Don't be sidetracked by an ordinary descriptive phrase that happens
这里只是碰巧含有国籍词。
to have a nationality in it. restaurant. We went to a good restaurant yesterday. Or
We went to an American restaurant yesterday。这里会使用同样的模式，
we went to an American restaurant yesterday. You would use the same pattern
因为国籍或多或少只是附带信息，比如 I had French toast for
where the nationality is more or less incidental in, I had French toast for
breakfast。另一方面，French fry 已经变成固定短语。三，American food。
breakfast. French fry, on the other hand, has become a set phrase. 3. American food.
Food 是弱词。我住在日本时从没吃过 American food。
Food is a weak word. I never ate American food when I lived in Japan.
teacher。这是描述性说法，所以重音落在 teacher 上。五，An English
4. An English teacher. This is a description so the stress is on teacher. 5. An English
teacher。这是固定短语，重音落在所教的学科上，
teacher. This is a set phrase. The stress is on the subject being taught, not on the
教师的国籍。法国教师、西班牙教师、历史教师，
nationality of the teacher. A French teacher, a Spanish teacher, a history
teacher。
teacher.